Guide to the Philip G. Zimbardo Papers SC0750
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Professional files, Series 3
  - Professional organizations (APA)
    - APA President-Elect Monitor questions (Box 116, Folder 61)
    - APA Election materials, 2000 Fall (Box 116, Folder 62)
    - Prez Year, 2002 (Box 116, Folder 63)
    - APA-Presidential review, 2002 (Box 116, Folder 64)
    - Drugs (Box 131, Folder 1)
    - T.F.-Drugs (Box 131, Folder 2)
    - APA Drugs (Box 131, Folder 3)
    - Drugs-APA TF (Box 131, Folder 4)
    - Drug TF (Box 131, Folder 5)
    - EXT Funding (Box 131, Folder 6)
    - APA Task Force on External Funding: final report (Box 131, Folder 7)
    - Policies of other orgs-Drugs (1 of 3) (Box 131, Folder 8)
    - Policies of other orgs-Drugs (2 of 3) (Box 131, Folder 9)
    - Policies of other orgs-Drugs (3 of 3) (Box 131, Folder 10)
    - APA abstract: Rationality/madness, 1981 (Box 131, Folder 11)
    - Associations-APA 1 (Box 131, Folder 12)
    - APA-Exploratorium (Box 131, Folder 13)
    - APA-Prevention (Box 131, Folder 14)
    - APA-Prevention (Box 131, Folder 15)
    - Hypnosis talk-APA, 2001 (Box 131, Folder 16)
    - APA, 2000 (Box 131, Folder 17)
    - APA, 2001 (Box 131, Folder 18)
    - APA, 1987 (Box 131, Folder 19)
    - APA, 2007 (Box 131, Folder 20)
    - TF External funding (Box 131, Folder 21)
    - APS PXSXS [Person X Situation X System Dynamics] reply Web and Observer, 2007 July (Box 131, Folder 22)
    - APA, 1976 (Box 131, Folder 23)
    - SPE interview, British AQA Psych review (Box 131, Folder 24)
    - Miller Award (Box 131, Folder 25)
    - APA Ethics & Interrogation (Box 131, Folder 26)
    - APA-Hilgard lecture, 2000 (Box 131, Folder 27)
    - Hilgard OH (Box 131, Folder 28)
    - American Psychiatric Association, 2002 May (Box 131, Folder 29)
    - APA-Drugs (Box 131, Folder 30)
    - APA Ext. funding drugs (Box 131, Folder 31)
    - TF Drugs report (Box 131, Folder 32)
    - APA Drugs (Box 131, Folder 33)
    - Educational Leadership Conference-closing remarks, 2001 Oct 30 (Box 131, Folder 34)
    - APA Pres. Track lecture (Box 157, Folder 34)
    - Clinician statement-APA (Box 157, Folder 35)
    - APA-Teachers (Box 157, Folder 36)
    - APA Drugs-Task Force (Box 157, Folder 37)
    - APA Convention [program], 2002 (Box 157, Folder 38)
    - PENS Critique-P. H. R., 2006 Sep (Box 157, Folder 39)
    - APA-Monitor on Psychology (President's column), 2002 Jun (Box 157, Folder 40)
    - APA-call for programs for 2010 (Box 157, Folder 41)
  - Professional organizations (other than APA)
    - WPA Historian, 1992 (Box 157, Folder 42)
    - CPA speech [accepting Lifetime Achievement Award], 2003 Apr 5 (Box 157, Folder 43)
    - Council of Scientific Society Presidents (Box 157, Folder 44)
    - Associations: Stanford Alumni (Box 157, Folder 45)
  - Speeches/eulogies
    - Elegy for Alex [Armour], 1983 Apr 15 (Box 158, Folder 38)
    - Eulogy for Margaret Zimbardo (Box 158, Folder 39)
    - Neal Miller-Eulogy (Box 158, Folder 40)
    - Carlo Piccione-Memorial Tribute, 1994 (Box 158, Folder 41)
    - Curt Banks-Eulogy, 1998 Jan 20 (Box 158, Folder 42)
  - Television and film
    - Candid Camera-Business/Contracts, 1992-1994 (Box 106, Folder 6)
    - Candid Camera-Funt interview for Psychology Today (Box 106, Folder 8)
    - Contract-Film Vides/Cristaldi, 1984 (Box 106, Folder 36)
    - The Human Zoo-Receipt and License Agreement (Box 102, Folder 55)
    - Prison Video-Vendor Data Sheets (Box 102, Folder 40)
    - Joyce Brothers (Box 153, Folder 1)
    - False alarms (Box 153, Folder 2)
    - BBC-TV (Box 153, Folder 3)
    - Testimonials: Allen Funt and others (Box 153, Folder 4)
    - Control (Box 153, Folder 5)
    - Dateline pitches (Box 153, Folder 6)
    - Rex Bloomstein, Nucleus Productions (Box 153, Folder 7)
    - Ronald Ridenhour (Box 153, Folder 8)
    - Children of Jonestown video-correspondence with Claire Crawford [Mason] (Box 153, Folder 9)
    - Media/Zim/Iraq-media interview list, 2004 May (Box 153, Folder 10)
    - NBC-Reality TV (Box 153, Folder 11)
    - Tyranny-BBC (Box 153, Folder 12)
    - Allen Funt (Box 153, Folder 13)
    - Philip G. Zimbardo-Prague, 2005 (Box 153, Folder 14)
    - WGBH Intro Psychology course (Box 153, Folder 15)
    - Discovering Psychology video modules (Box 153, Folder 16)
    - HBO contract, 1995 July (Box 153, Folder 17)
    - Discovering Psychology. Evaluation: viewer feedback letters (Box 153, Folder 18)
    - Pilot-evaluations (Box 153, Folder 19)
    - Discovering Psychology. WGBH (Box 153, Folder 20)
    - Candid Camera. Films at Cornell [catalog of CC collection at Cornell] (Box 153, Folder 21)
    - Discovering Psychology. PBS TV (Box 153, Folder 22)
    - Das Experiment (Box 153, Folder 23)
    - Human Zoo movie-London Weekend Television (Box 153, Folder 24)
    - KCET-Social Psychology. David Myers (Box 153, Folder 25)
    - Palo Alto University, Dr. Phil (Box 153, Folder 26)
    - Freud (Box 153, Folder 27)
    - Discovering Psychology calendar, 1990-1991 (Box 153, Folder 28)
    - Adding Vividness to Social Psychology-Videos (Box 153, Folder 29)
    - Wake Up Louisiana (Box 153, Folder 30)
    - Real Psychology (Box 153, Folder 31)
    - Real Psychology (Box 153, Folder 32)
    - Reality TV (Box 153, Folder 33)
    - Palo Alto University. Prof. Dr. Phil, 2010 (Box 153, Folder 34)
- Publications and writing, Series 4
  This series is comprised of manuscripts and related materials from the many articles and books Dr. Zimbardo authored or co-authored, as well as some unpublished writings. Included are typed and handwritten manuscripts, research notes, promotional materials, reviews of publications, and related correspondence.
  These publications and writings are arranged in the following subseries:
  Papers and articles. Includes articles and papers authored or co-authored by Zimbardo. Works in this series are arranged by title or subject.
  Publications by date. Works are arranged by year, and span from 1950-2003.
  Books. Includes various drafts, typescripts, and notes by Zimbardo. Most are related to the introductory psychology textbook, Psychology and Life, co-authored by Zimbardo.
  Files are arranged into three subseries, which include: papers and articles; publications by date; and books.
  - Publications by date, Accession ARCH-2005-031
    - Bibliography (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - 1950s (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - 1960-1961 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - 1963 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - 1964-1965 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - 1966 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - 1967-1968 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - 1969 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - 1970 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Canvassing for Peace, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - 1972 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - 1973 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - 1974-1975 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - 1977 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - 1978-1979 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - 1980-1984 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - 1985-1989 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - 1991-1995 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - 1996-1999 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - 2000-2003 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Books
    - Psychology and Life, 13th ed., Chap. 6: Life Span Development (1 of 2) (Box 95, Folder 1)
    - Psychology and Life, 13th ed., Chap. 6: Life Span Development (2 of 2) (Box 95, Folder 2)
    - Psychology and Life, 13th ed., Chap. 7: Sensation (1 of 2) (Box 95, Folder 3)
    - Psychology and Life, 13th ed., Chap. 7: Sensation (2 of 2) (Box 95, Folder 4)
    - Psychology and Life, 13th ed., Chap. 8: Perception (1 of 2) (Box 95, Folder 5)
    - Psychology and Life, 13th ed., Chap. 8: Perception (2 of 2) (Box 95, Folder 6)
    - Psychology and Life, 13th ed., Chap. 9: Learning and Behavior Analysis (1 of 2) (Box 95, Folder 7)
    - Psychology and Life, 13th ed., Chap. 9: Learning and Behavior Analysis (2 of 2) (Box 95, Folder 8)
    - Psychology and Life, 13th ed., Chap. 10: Remembering and Forgetting (1 of 2) (Box 95, Folder 9)
    - Psychology and Life, 13th ed., Chap. 10: Remembering and Forgetting (2 of 2) (Box 95, Folder 10)
    - Psychology and Life, 13th ed., Chap. 11: Cognitive Psychology (1 of 2)Psychology and Life, 13th ed., Chap. 11: Cognitive Psychology (1 of 2) (Box 95, Folder 11)
    - Psychology and Life, 13th ed., Chap. 11: Cognitive Psychology (2 of 2) (Box 95, Folder 12)
    - Psychology and Life, 13th ed., Chap. 12: Motivational Dynamics (1 of 2) (Box 95, Folder 13)
    - Psychology and Life, 13th ed., Chap. 12: Motivational Dynamics (2 of 2) (Box 95, Folder 14)
    - Psychology and Life, 13th ed., Chap. 13: Emotion, Stress, and Health Psychology (1 of 2) (Box 95, Folder 15)
    - Psychology and Life, 13th ed., Chap. 13: Emotion, Stress, and Health Psychology (2 of 2) (Box 95, Folder 16)
    - Psychology and Life, 13th ed., Chap. 14: Understanding Human Personality (1 of 2) (Box 95, Folder 17)
    - Psychology and Life, 13th ed., Chap. 14: Understanding Human Personality (2 of 2) (Box 95, Folder 18)
    - Psychology and Life, 13th ed., Chap. 15: Assessing Individual Differences (1 of 2) (Box 95, Folder 19)
    - Psychology and Life, 13th ed., Chap. 15: Assessing Individual Differences (2 of 2) (Box 95, Folder 20)
    - Psychology and Life, 13th ed., Chap. 16: Social Psychology (1 of 2) (Box 95, Folder 21)
    - Psychology and Life, 13th ed., Chap. 16: Social Psychology (2 of 2) (Box 95, Folder 22)
    - Psychology and Life, 12th ed., Complete Reviews: Reviewers 1-5, 1990 Jul (Box 95, Folder 23)
    - Psychology and Life, 12th ed., Complete Reviews: Reviewers 6-8, 1990 Jul (Box 95, Folder 24)
    - Psychology and Life, 12th ed., Complete Reviews: Reviewers 9-12, 1990 Jul (Box 95, Folder 25)
    - Psychology and Life, 12th ed., Complete Reviews: Reviewers 13-16, 1990 Jul (Box 95, Folder 26)
    - Psychology and Life, 12th ed., Complete Reviews: Reviewers 17-21, 1990 Jul (Box 95, Folder 27)
    - Psychology and Life, 12th ed., Complete Reviews: Reviewers 22-26, 1990 Jul (Box 95, Folder 28)
    - Psychology and Life, 12th ed., Reviewer Comments by Topic: General and Comparative Analysis, 1990 Jul (Box 95, Folder 29)
    - Psychology and Life, 12th ed., Reviewer Comments by Topic: Organization, 1990 Jul (Box 95, Folder 30)
    - Psychology and Life, 12th ed., Reviewer Comments by Topic: Coverage, 1990 Jul (Box 95, Folder 31)
    - Psychology and Life, 12th ed., Reviewer Comments by Topic: Presentation, 1990 Jul (Box 95, Folder 32)
    - Psychology and Life, 12th ed., Reviewer Comments by Topic: Style and Level, 1990 Jul (Box 95, Folder 33)
    - Psychology and Life, 12th ed., Reviewer Comments by Topic: General, 1990 Jul (Box 95, Folder 34)
    - Psychology and Life, 12th ed., Reviewer Comments by Topic: Competition, 1990 Jul (Box 95, Folder 35)
    - Psychology and Life, 13th ed., Chap. 18: Therapies for Personal Change (Box 83, Folder 14)
    - Psychology and Life, 13th ed., Chap. 17: Abnormal Psychology (Box 83, Folder 15)
    - Psychology and Life, 13th ed., Chap. 1: Intro, 1990 Sep (Box 83, Folder 16)
    - References for Psychology and Life, 13th ed. (1) (Box 83, Folder 17)
    - References for Psychology and Life, 13th ed. (2) (Box 83, Folder 18)
    - Psychology and Life, 13th ed., Chap. 2: Methods (Box 83, Folder 19)
    - Psychology and Life, 13th ed., Appendix + Misc. (Box 83, Folder 20)
    - Psychology and Life, 13th ed., Chap. 3: Biopsychology and Neuroscience (Box 83, Folder 21)
    - Psychology and Life, 13th ed., Chap. 4: Consciousness (Box 83, Folder 22)
    - Psychology and Life, 13th ed., Chap. 5: Devo. (Box 83, Folder 23)
    - Discovering Psychology (Box 156, Folder 31)
    - Psychology and Life, 13th ed. (Box 156, Folder 32)
    - Enriching Psychological Research on Disability (Box 156, Folder 33)
    - Brockman, Inc. (Box 156, Folder 34)
    - "Transforming Good People into Pepetrators of Evil: Can We Reverse the Process?" Naples Chapter (Box 156, Folder 35)
    - "Commentary on Part III: Developmental Outcomes and Clinical Perspectives," Henderson, Zimbardo (Box 156, Folder 36)
    - Social Psychology and Modern Life, Introduction by Zimbardo (Box 156, Folder 37)
    - Polish Text-Promotional Material (Box 156, Folder 38)
    - 14: Loss of Contact with Reality: Psychosis (Box 156, Folder 39)
    - Chapter Intro 14a: Sick! Sick, Sick? (Box 156, Folder 40)
    - Shy Child-Italy (Permissions) (Box 156, Folder 41)
    - 9/11-Foreword (Box 156, Folder 42)
    - Chapter 19-Public Education of Psychology: An Interview with Philip G. Zimbardo, Ph.D. (Box 156, Folder 43)
    - Psychology and Life, Golden Edition (Box 156, Folder 44)
    - Prison Book (Box 156, Folder 45)
    - Psych & You Calendar, 1978 (Box 100, Folder 59)
    - Psych & Life Calendar, 1978 (Box 100, Folder 60)
    - Psych & Life Newsletters, 1975-1978 (Box 100, Folder 61)
    - Psych & Life, 9th: Puzzle/Front Matter (Box 100, Folder 62)
    - Psych & Life, 11th: Brochure (Box 100, Folder 63)
    - Proposal for Social Psych Reader/Festinger Interview, 1967-1968 (Box 110, Folder 7)
  - Papers and articles
    - "The Chilling Effect of Surveillance: Deindividuation and Reactance," ONR Technical Report Z-15, May 1975; Accession ARCH-2005-031 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - "Constructing Time After Death: The Transcendental-Future Time Perspective", circa 1996; Accession ARCH-2005-031 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - "Corrections: Perspectives on Research, Policy and Impact," ONR Technical Report Z-13, 1975; Accession ARCH-2005-031 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - "Effects of system and social variables on gender differences in communication and team decision making," ONR Technical Report Z-82-02, 1982; Accession ARCH-2005-031 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - "The Modification of Selective Recall of Central and Incidental Task Features by Emotional Arousal," ONR Technical Report Z-02, 1970; Accession ARCH-2005-031 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - "A Passion for Psychology: Teaching it Charismatically, Writing about it Engagingly, and Integrating Teaching and Research Synergistically", circa 1994; Accession ARCH-2005-031 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - "The personal and cultural dynamics of shyness: a comparison between Israelis, American Jews and Americans", circa 1977; Accession ARCH-2005-031 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - "Physical Integration and Social Segregation of Northern Negro College Students (1953, 1963 and 1965)", 1966; Accession ARCH-2005-031 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - "The Political Psychology of Terrorist Alarms", 2003; Accession ARCH-2005-031 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - "The Politics of Persuasion," ONR Technical Report Z-06, 1971; Accession ARCH-2005-031 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - "Present Time Perspective as a Predictor of Risky Driving", Accession ARCH-2005-031 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - "Psychological and system variables in team problem solving: Experimental studies of computer-mediated participation," ONR Technical Report Z-82-01, 1982; Accession ARCH-2005-031 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - "The Psychology of Evil: A Situationist Perspective on Recruiting Good People to Engage in Anti-Social Acts", circa 1995; Accession ARCH-2005-031 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - "Sexism Springs Eternal—in The Reader's Digest", April 1974; Accession ARCH-2005-031 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - "Shame and Anger in Chronic Shyness", 1998; Accession ARCH-2005-031 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - "The Silent Prison of Shyness", November 1974; Accession ARCH-2005-031 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - "Social Determinants of Group Loyalty, Innovation, and Activism," ONR Technical Report Z-11, Accession ARCH-2005-031 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - "A Social-Psychological Analysis of Vandalism: Making Sense of Senseless Violence," ONR Technical Report Z-05, Dec 1970; Accession ARCH-2005-031 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Stanford Time Perspective Inventory, Accession ARCH-2005-031 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - "Whose Time It Is I Think I Know: Research on Time Perspectives", 1994; Accession ARCH-2005-031 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Assorted writings, Accession ARCH-2005-031 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - "Coercion and Compliance: The Psychology of Police Confessions" (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - "Cults go to high school: A theoretical and empirical analysis of the initial stage in the recruitment process." (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Endorsement of Garcia/Keough Workbook on Gender, Race, & Ethnicity, "Psychology of Gender, Race, and Ethnicity: An Introduction with Readings and Projects", 1996 Jan 31 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Publications: Directory of Publishers (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Addison-Wesley, 1989 Sept (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - ONR Technical Report Abstracts TRI-17, 1991 Mar 6 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Gage/Harper, 1990 Jun 5 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Harper & Collins - "Psychology and Life", 1991 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Holt, Rinehart & Winston, 1991 Apr 17 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - McGraw-Hill, 1991-1994 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Psych. 1 Winter 1977, Research Frontier Articles, 1988-1989 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Scott, Foresman--Newsletters '73'74'75'76, 1973-1976 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Invitations to Review (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Invitations to Publish, Circa 1972-circa 1994 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Marketing Blurb (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Permissions to Publish, 1990-1997 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Claremont-McKenna Graduation Address, 1994 May 15 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - "The Culture of Violence in the U.S.: No Simple Solutions For the Complex Violence Equation", 1994 Mar 18 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - "An Evening with Allen Funt," S.F. WPA Convention, 1991 Apr 26 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Al Hastorf Retirement Dinner, P.Z. Tribute, 1989 Dec 3 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - "Adding Vividness to Social Psych Lectures: Video Supplements", 1993 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - 1987-APA, The Mentor Tradition... (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Stanford Psychology Dept. Commencement Address, 1985 Jun 17 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Invitations to Speak: Commencement Address, Lick-Wilmerding High School, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - APA-1975, Child Abuse... (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - "Dehumanization in Institutional Settings", 1973 Aug 30 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - "The Ecological Orientation: Its implications for psychology, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - "Objective Measurement of Subjective States: Externalizing Internal Dispositions." Zimbardo/Ebbesen/Fraser (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - "On almost being the first black psychologist at Yale..." PGZ. (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Publications: "Psych Today" 15th Anniversary Issue, 1982 May (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Freshman Orientation Lecture, "Will I Make It?", 1969 Aug 26 (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Reviews by PGZ, Circa 1970-1997 (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Review of E. Aron's "The Highly Sensitive Person", 1996 Jan 30 (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Darwin on Shyness by P.G.Z., 1995 Jul 10 (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - Review of "The Story of Psychology" by Morton Hunt, 1984, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Review of Deikman, Arthur J., "Cults in Everyday Life," Contemp. Psych, 1992, Vol 37 (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - Introduction to P.M. Middlebrook's "Social Psychology & Modern Life." New York: Alfred A. Knopf, 1974. (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - "Becoming a Sexist--in one easy Laugh: Sexism in the Reader's Digest," Zimbardo and Wendy Meadow (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - Various Zimbardo Reviews, 1974, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - "Misunderstanding Shyness: The Counter Attack," Psychology Today., 1978 (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - "A Reply to Jordan's Attack on Dissonance Theory," Zimbardo (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - Book Review: Prediction and Outcome, "Yale Scientific," Mar. 60, Zimbardo, 1960 Mar (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - Book Review: Individual in Society, "Cont. Psychol.," Aug. 63, 1963 Aug (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - Forewords, "The Psychology of Helping and Altruism: Problems and Puzzles." (Box 3, Folder 45)
    - Foreword to J.M. Steiner's "Power, Politics & Social Change in National Socialist Germany"--1976 (Box 3, Folder 46)
    - UCB Psych 2 Comments on Zim. and Gerrig, "Psychology and Life" (14th Ed.), 1996 Dec (Box 3, Folder 47)
    - Publications--Reviews of PGZ's work, Circa 1970-1979 (Box 3, Folder 48)
    - Review of "Psych of Attitude Change" (Contemp Psych, 1993) (Box 3, Folder 49)
    - Review of "Discovering Psychology" videos, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 50)
    - Review of "Psych. & Life," 9th Ed. in Teaching Psychology, 1976 Dec 3 (Box 3, Folder 51)
    - Review of "Individual in Society: A textbook of Social Psychology," D. Drech, R.S. Crutchfield, E. L. Ballachey. Contemp. Psych., 8, 294-296, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 52)
    - Review of Zimbardo's APS Talk, 1996, 1996 Jul/Aug (Box 3, Folder 53)
    - "Giving away psychology in the 80s" (Psych Today 1/90), 1990 Jan (Box 3, Folder 54)
    - "A World of Their Own" (Chicago Tribune) (shyness), 1995 Oct 9 (Box 3, Folder 55)
    - "On the shy side" (Muskegon Chronicle) (shyness), 1995 Sep 26 (Box 3, Folder 56)
    - "Are You Shy?" (Psych. Today Nov./Dec. '95) (shyness), 1995 Nov/Dec (Box 3, Folder 57)
    - "Improving the human condition" (The Academic Author 1996, profile of PGZ) (Box 3, Folder 58)
    - "The bold & the bashful" (shyness) (Ambassador magazine), 1996 Feb (Box 3, Folder 59)
    - "Bittersweet Memories of a Study Gone Haywire", 1996 Oct (Box 3, Folder 60)
    - "Are Blacks More or Less Shy Than Other Races?", 1996 Apr 8 (Box 3, Folder 61)
    - "They rely on ATMs, work graveyard hours..." (Times) (shyness), 1996 (Box 3, Folder 62)
    - "Demystifying the Stanford Prison Study" by Stuart Carr, BPS, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 63)
    - "The Prison's Power" by Peter Salovey, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 64)
    - "Teaching Social Psych's Indispensable Concept," review by Pratkanis of Attitude, Change, & Soc Influence, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 65)
    - "Cruelty, Ethics & Experimentation" by Dr. McDermott, "British Psych.", 1993 Oct (Box 3, Folder 66)
    - "The Stanford Prison Experiment: Still Powerful After All These Years," Stanford Report, 1997 Jan 8 (Box 3, Folder 67)
    - "PGZ: Profile of an Experimental Social Psychologist" by McDermott (Box 3, Folder 68)
    - "Zimbardo" by Joan Hamilton (Stanford Magazine), 1990 Sep (Box 3, Folder 69)
    - Publications: "Zimbardo - Solving the Maze" by C. Bruck in Human Behavior, 1976 Apr (Box 3, Folder 70)
    - "Ethics," M. Hunt article focused on Zimbardo, 1982 Sep 12 (Box 3, Folder 71)
    - Zimbardo - publications list as of April '98, 1998 Apr (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Pubs--Corrections to be made, Circa 1999 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Publications and reports, PGZ, 1996 Jan 23 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - "Social Psychology: What it is, where it came from, and where it's headed" by PGZ, 1984 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - "Understanding the Complexity of Human Emotion..." Zimbardo, 1996 (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - "On Resisting Social Influence" by PGZ, 1979 (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - "Mind Control in 1984" by PGZ + other mind control publications, 1980-1984 (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - Reviews by Phil Zimbardo, Contemporary Psychology (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - Pubs on Deindividuation, 1975, 1978 (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - On Personalized Instruction, PGZ, 1977 (Box 20, Folder 10)
    - Pubs. on Prison by PGZ, 1975-1994 (Box 20, Folder 11)
    - The Psychology of Evil by PGZ, 1978, 1995 (Box 20, Folder 12)
    - Pubs. by PGZ on TEAM PROBLEM SOLVING, 1979-1983 (Box 20, Folder 13)
    - Forewords by PGZ, 1980 (Box 20, Folder 14)
    - Publications on POLITICS, 1980-1997 (Box 20, Folder 15)
    - Zimbardo on Teaching Psych, various articles, 1975-1996 (Box 20, Folder 16)
    - Zimbardo publications on CULTS, 1980-1992 (Box 20, Folder 17)
    - Time Perspective, publications and inventories by PGZ, 1981-1999 (Box 20, Folder 18)
    - Publications on hypnotizability, 1979-1993 (Box 20, Folder 19)
    - Zimbardo in Psychology Today, 1975-1982 (Box 20, Folder 20)
    - Shyness Publications (Box 20, Folder 21)
    - "Induced Hearing Deficit Generates Experimental Paranoia", 1981 Jun 26 (Box 20, Folder 22)
    - "Attitudes and Attitude Change: A Convo with PGZ", 1975 (Box 20, Folder 23)
    - "Sexism Spring Eternal," PGZ in Reader's Digest (Box 20, Folder 24)